Jack E. Reynolds papers, 1950-1992
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Jack E. Reynolds Papers, 1950-1992
MS 147
Reynolds, Jack E.
Contains letters from customers and colleagues, writers, and artists; major correspondents are J. Frank Dobie, Helen S. Giffen, Carl Hertzog, Lawrence Clark Powell, Ralph W. Yarborough, and David Magee. Also present is material by and about Reynolds, Dobie, Hertzog, Powell, Yarborough, and Magee; as well as about Ross Santee.
2.1 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Jack E. Reynolds was a bookseller, specializing in Western Americana; his store was located in Van Nuys, California.
Organization
This collection is organized into four series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1950-1992
Series II: Catalogs, 1958-1975
Series III: David Magee Materials, 1958-1976
Series IV: Miscellaneous Materials, 1953-1965
Scope and Content Note
Contains letters from customers and colleagues, writers, and artists; major correspondents are J. Frank Dobie, Helen S. Giffen, Carl Hertzog, Lawrence Clark Powell, Ralph W. Yarborough, and David Magee. Also present is material by and about Reynolds, Dobie, Hertzog, Powell, Yarborough, and Magee; as well as about Ross Santee. An original Santee watercolor is included in his file. Proof copies are present of Magee's book Infinite Riches, and Powell's book A Southwestern Century, published by Reynolds in 1958. With the Powell materials are two engraving plates used for its cover illustration, by Tom Lea. The special "occasional" catalogs produced by Reynolds include original essays by select authors, and are accompanied by letters commenting on the issues. Photographs depict the first and second bookstores, Reynolds, Powell, Dobie, and Santee.
Magee, David Bickersteth, 1905-1977; Reynolds, Jack E. -- Archives; Hertzog, Carl; Dobie, J. Frank (James Frank), 1888-1964; Giffen, Helen S. (Helen Smith), 1893- -- Correspondence; Powell, Lawrence Clark, 1906-; Lea, Tom, 1907-; Santee, Ross, 1889-1965; J.E. Reynolds, Bookseller -- Archives; Booksellers and bookselling -- California; Antiquarian booksellers -- Correspondence; Bookstores -- California -- Pictorial works; Catalogs, Booksellers' -- California -- Specimens; Correspondence; Manuscripts; Catalogs; Photographs
Separated Material
Books received with this collection have been removed and catalogued separately. An inventory of these books is available at the repository.
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1950-1992
  - Adams, Ramon. 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cisneros, Jose. 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - De Yong, Joe. 1958-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dobie, J. Frank. 1953-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
  - Dobie, Bertha McKee. 1956-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from others regarding J. Frank Dobie. 1956-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dawson, Glen. 1970-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hertzog, Carl. 1957-1984 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Hutchinson, William Henry. 1960-1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lea, Tom. (Testimonial Dinner, El Paso). September, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Powell, Lawrence Clark. 1954-1984 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Winterich, John Tracy. 1954-1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Yarborough, Ralph Webster. 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Also copy of Potomac Corral Dust (Spring 1967) with excerpts of Yarborough talk, and copy of talk: "J. Frank Dobie, Man and Friend."
  - Various Individuals: 1953-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Armitage, Merle, 1957-1968
    Corle, Edwin, 1953-1956
    Dobie, Dudley R., 1958-1964
    Hanna, Archibald, 1969-1992
    Lauritzen, Jonreed, 1961-1962
    Powell, Donald M., 1968-1987
    Rittenhouse, Jack D., 1961-1965
    Wellman, Paul I., 1960
    Woodward, Arthur, 1956-1960
  - Collectors, Dealers, Librarians, etc. 1953-1991 (Box 2A, Folder 10-12)
  - Western Artists (various). 1950-1968 (Box 2A, Folder 13)
    Anderson, Andy, September 18, 1950
    Beeler, Joe, March 26 & April 15, 1968
    Bugbee, H. D., May 21, 1950
    Kihn, W. Langdon, November 9, 1950
    Leigh, W. R., December 8, 1950
    Wieghorst, Olaf, April 18, 1961
  - Southwest Conference (suggested revival of). 1960 (Box 2A, Folder 14)
  - University of Oklahoma Press. 1954, 1972 (Box 2A, Folder 15)
    Correspondence relating to Press objections to quotations from Six Guns and Saddle Leather in Reynolds Catalog #21.
- Series II: Catalogs, 1958-1975
  - Catalog #50, with essay by J. Frank Dobie. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Catalog #56, on Custer, with introduction by James Hutchins. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Catalog #58, on Charles P. Everitt, with introduction by J. Frank Dobie, and manuscript partly in Dobie's hand. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Catalog #61, on Eugene Manlove Rhodes, with essays by W. H. Hutchinson and W. C. Tuttle. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Catalog #66, on Ross Santee, with essays by Carl Dentzel, J. Frank Dobie, J. C. Dykes, W. H. Hutchinson and Jonreed Lauritzen; correspondence with Ross Santee. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Catalog #80, on Robert G. Cowan, with Cowan introduction. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Catalog #81, on Pete Martinez, with original etching and photos. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Catalog #84, on Dorothy Stauffer Hay, with manuscripts of introductions, photographs, and prints of Hay's work. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Catalog #90, on The West, with manuscript of introductory essay by Ralph Yarborough, and correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Catalog #99, on J. Frank Dobie, with letters from Bertha Dobie. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Catalog #129, on Will Rogers. Includes letters from Will Rogers, Jr. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Catalog #140, on American Indians. Correspondence with David H. Miller. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Catalog #141, on Ward Ritchie and Southern California Printers. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Series III: David Magee Materials, 1958-1976
  - Correspondence. 1958-1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Infinite Riches (Typescript). (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Infinite Riches (Page proofs). (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The Golden Cave (Typescript, final version with corrections). (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - A Flag for Christmas and Indian Corn: A Thanksgiving Extravaganza. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Interview with David Magee, San Francisco. April 8, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Transcript of tape made by Ruth Teiser.
  - First catalog compiled by David Magee (2 copies). (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Grabhorn Press Items (miscellaneous, signed by David Magee). (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Life and Death of Athena, an Owlet from the Parthenon." (Page proofs, holograph and typed manuscripts of Magee's introduction). (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous Materials, 1953-1965
  - Reynolds, Jack (articles by and about). (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (J. Frank Dobie, Jack Reynolds, Reynolds' shops). (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Hertzog, Carl: Miscellaneous publications and ephemera. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Powell, Lawrence Clark: "Christmas...The Southwest...and J. Frank Dobie." (Typescript, page proofs, correspondence, etc.). (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Powell, Lawrence Clark: A Southwestern Century. (Dummy, dust wrapper, announcement, correspondence, etc.). (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Powell, Lawrence Clark: Miscellaneous articles. (Typescripts, reprints. Inscribed). (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Two original plates of Tom Lea illustrations for A Southwestern Century. (Box 5)